Savannah **Hammerton**

University of Georgia College of Public Health

🛘 423 544 2453 | 🔀 savannah.hammerton@uga.edu | 🎢 smhammerton.com | 🖸 smhammerton | 🛅 smhammerton

About

Graduate student working towards PhD in Epidemiology & Biostatistics (concentration in Data Analysis and Modeling). Particular interest and research emphasis in infectious diseases, infectious disease dynamics and modeling, and data analysis. Past experience in healthcare, providing strong contextual understanding of disease determinants, prevention, treatment, and outcomes, as well as an understanding of the real world implications of public health research and practice on individuals. This experience also drives context-aware data analytic approaches to answering epidemiological questions. Passionate and driven to build a career that benefits others.

Education

University of Georgia Athens, GA

PHD EPIDEMIOLOGY & BIOSTATISTICS (DATA ANALYSIS & MODELING EMPHASIS)

University of Georgia Athens, GA

MS EPIDEMIOLOGY & BIOSTATISTICS (EPIDEMIOLOGY EMPHASIS) | CERTIFICATE IN INFECTIOUS DISEASE EPIDEMIOLOGY

2020-2022 **Columbus State University**

BS, HEALTH SCIENCE

Chattanooga College Chattanooga, TN

DIPLOMA, PRACTICAL NURSING (SUMMA CUM LAUDE, DIRECTOR'S AWARD FOR CONSISTENT ACADEMIC AND CLINICAL

Columbus, GA

2018-2020

2014-2015

2022-Present

Relevant Experience _____

University of Georgia, Department of Epidemiology & Biostatistics

Athens, GA 2022-Present

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISANT

 Assist Dr. Andreas Handel in research for the Center for Influenza Vaccine Research for High-Risk Populations (CIVR-HRP) grant at the University of Georgia. Aid in research and data analysis on influenza vaccines, particularly data related to universal influenza vaccine development.

University of Georgia, Department of Epidemiology & Biostatistics

Athens, GA

GRADUATE DEPARTMENTAL ASSISANT

· Assist in administrative departmental tasks, faculty retreats/meeting planning, and department event planning. Create and maintain spreadsheets on department classes, students, etc. Develop presentation materials and assist in orientation. Generate documents with information on degree programs, Graduate School processes, etc. Participate in research with Dr. Jose Cordero, planning and implementing a systematic review of environmental exposures and preterm birth.

Georgetown Behavioral Health Institute

Georgetown, TX

LICENSED VOCATIONAL NURSE

2016-2016

• LVN working on adolescent male and female units, military unit. Conducted medication administration, milieu management, conflict resolution, patient chart management. Responsible for verbal de-escalation of agitated patients, medical complication and event management. Aided in coordination of care between all health care providers.

Encompass Home Health Pediatrics

Temple, TX

LICENSED VOCATIONAL NURSE

2016-2016

 Provided pediatric patient care for those needing 24-hour care or on hospice. Responsible for nutrition, hygiene, infection control, medication administration, respiratory status maintenance. Provided support to families of patients and socialization to patients throughout shifts.

Research

Examining antibodies as correlates of protection against norovirus clinical outcomes

University of Georgia 2021-Present

MS THESIS PROJECT, ADVISOR - DR. ANDREAS HANDEL

University of Georgia

Systematic review of norovirus challenge studies

2022-Present

CO-AUTHOR

Preterm birth and the environment

RESEARCH ASSISANTSHIP, DR. JOSE CORDERO

University of Georgia 2021-2022

Prenatal exposure to flame retardants and adverse pregnancy outcomes: A systematic review

University of Georgia

CONTRIBUTOR 2021-2022

Certifications

Social and Behavioral Research

CITI Program 2021

Epidemics - The Dynamics of Infectious Diseases

Coursera 2020

Certificate in Infectious Diseases and Disease Control

ALLEGRA LEARNING SOLUTIONS 2020

Essentials of Public Health Research

CITI Program 2019

Research Involving Human Subjects

CITI Program 2019

Service_

Athens Water Festival Athens, GA

VOLUNTEER September 2022

Aided in setup and breakdown of annual Athens Water Festival. Collaborated with other volunteers to engage and educate children on marine
life, Georgia biodiversity, and geology.

Graduate Scholars of Epidemiology & Biostatistics (GSEB)

University of Georgia College of Public Health

Secretary 2021-2022

• Managed fundraising events and community food pantry. Planned and recorded regular executive board and general body meetings. Developed and led events open to department and college students. Maintained communication with department members to assess student needs and announce organization events. Maintained records for future executive board members.

Skills_

Data Analysis

Primary coding language: R \mid Additional experience in: SAS, Stata, SPSS

Literature Searches and Management

Endnote, Endnote Click, Zotero

Laboratory Biosafety Level 2 Practices

EXPERIENCE IN SAFE MICROBIOLOGY LABORATORY PRACTICES WHEN WORKING WITH HUMAN PATHOGENS

Infectious Disease Modeling

Understanding of infectious disease modeling concepts, and experience in fitting infectious disease models

Organization

SKILLED IN MANAGING MULTIPLE TASKS AND PROJECTS, MAINTAINING HIGH QUALITY OF WORK

Communication

EXPERIENCE IN CLINICAL, RESEARCH, AND PRIVATE GROUPS REQUIRING LARGE AMOUNTS OF COLLABORATION

Health Education

HAVE PROVIDED HEALTH EDUCATION IN BOTH CLINICAL AND NON-CLINICAL SETTINGS

Leadership/Management

EXPERIENCE IN MANAGEMENT, LEADERSHIP OF MULTIPLE EMPLOYEES

Organizations _____

Graduate Scholars of Epidemiology & Biostatistics (GSEB)

Center for the Ecology of Infectious Diseases (CEID)

Eta Sigma Gamma (ESG) | Health Science Honor Society

American Public Health Association (APHA)

Council of State and Territorial Epidemiologists (CSTE)

Member

2021-Present

Member

2021-Present

Member

2019-2020

Member 2019-Present

Member

2021-Present